Connor A. Olson

Woodinville, WA

connorolson123@gmail.com

206-799-6553 linkedin.com/in/connorolson4

NETWORK ENGINEER

Critical-thinking networking specialist that loves to learn and solve problems. Thrives in fast-paced environments and can excel individually or in a team. Customer-focused and sees projects through from beginning to end. Versatile background familiar with all areas of IT. Core competencies include:

- Routing Protocols
- Network Hardware
- Firewalls
- Computer Networking
- Wireless Networks
- Network Security
- Edge Networking
- Server Deployment
- Data Center Install
- Helpdesk Support
- Technical Troubleshooting
- Customer Service
- Problem Solving
- Systems
 Administration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Hardware: Routers, Switches, Access Points, Controllers, Servers, Storage Arrays **Software**: Clearpass, Airwave, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Word, Open Source, Microsoft Windows, Java, SQL

Network Management: Salesbuilder, One Config Advanced, One Config Simple, Iris, TCP/IP, BGP, OSPF, DHCP, HTTP/S, IRF, VSF, ARM, ClientMatch, Activity Tracker in Clearpass, IDS/DPS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Apprentice Carpenter, Bellevue, WA

October 2019 - December 2020

Performed clean installations aligning with customer specifications. Coordinated allocation of human resources and materials to complete projects. Communicated complex information to managers, customers, and peers.

- Designed and read schematics to deliver complex solutions to specific guidelines.
- Delivered solutions under intense time constraints and persevered through many obstacles to finish projects.
- Led junior team members with professionalism to learn and install systems according to best known methods.
- Ensured high levels of quality by applying a strong attention to detail and solving difficult problems with agility.

CB Technologies, Inc., Kirkland, Washington Solution Architect, Network Administrator

September 2015 - October 2019

Liaison and support administrator for customers of Aruba and HPE networking equipment. Maintained cutting edge understanding of current versions of hardware and software. Escalated network issues to next level for resolution.

- Deployed complete systems in world class data centers.
- Configured servers and networking equipment.
- Provided strong technical networking and Aruba value to sales teams, engineering teams, prospects and customers.
- Developed skill in security of built systems with firewalls and encryption.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Alpharetta, GA

June 2016 - March 2017

Solutions Architect Candidate

- Engaged in a comprehensive training program for networking, storage, server, cloud, and Synergy systems.
- Successfully completed the 10-month training program for solution architects.

American Red Cross, Syracuse, NY

January 2015 - May 2015

Program Manager - Social Media

- Collaborated with teams to solve problems and solutions in support of Red Cross public image and engagement.
- Educated and evangelized technology to teams including software and web platforms.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - Information Management and Technology, School of Information Studies at Syracuse University, NY

Professional Development

Supercompute and HP-CAST - Denver, CO Aruba Atmosphere - Las Vegas, NV Voltage/SecureData - Palo Alto, CA Aruba Clearpass Bootcamp - Portland, OR ACMP Bootcamp - Seattle, WA Impini RFID - Seattle, WA

CERTIFICATIONS

Aruba Certified Mobility Professional (ACMP) V6.4 HPE ATP - Server Solutions V3 HPE ATP - Storage Solutions V2

VOLUNTEERING

Coach, Inglemoor High School Youth Lacrosse Delta Tau Delta Fraternity, Gamma Omicron Chapter, Active Brother Syracuse University Ski Team March 2018 - Present